Although, this visual shows us that
رغم ما سبق، يرينا هذا العرض المرئي
the white wine samples has slightly higher average quality ratings,
أن عينات النبيذ الأبيض لها معدل أعلى بقليل في تصنيفات الجودة،
it would be nice if we could get more details on where that's coming from.
وسيكون هذا جيدًا إذا تمكَّننا من الحصول على تفاصيل أكثر حول ما يجعل هذا يحدث.
Let's put a more detailed bar chart,
فلنضع رسمًا بيانيًا شريطيًا أكثر تفصيلًا
counts for each quality rating by color.
بحيث يحسب كل تصنيف للجودة وفقًا للون.
We can groupby quality and color to do this.
يمكننا التصنيف وفقًا للجودة واللون كي نفعل هذا.
Because these are counts,
ولأن هذه أعداد
the values for all the columns will be the same.
فستكون قيم جميع الأعمدة متطابقة؛
So we'll just pick an arbitrary one.
لذا سنلتقط قيمة عشوائية واحدة فحسب.
That's close, but there are several things that can improve at this plot.
هذا قريب مما نريده، لكن هناك العديد من الأشياء التي يمكننا تحسينها في هذا المخطط.
First, there's clearly more white samples than red samples.
أولًا، يتضح أن هناك عينات من النبيذ الأبيض أكثر من عينات النبيذ الأحمر،
So it's hard to make a fair comparison, we just count.
لذا من الصعب إجراء مقارنة عادلة بينهما؛ فقط نحن نحسب الأعداد.
To balance this out,
ولكي نجعل الأمر متوازنًا،
let's divide each count by the total count for that color to use proportions instead.
دعونا نقسم كل عدد على العدد الكلي لذلك اللون كي نستخدم النسب بدلًا منه.
That looks a lot better.
هذا يبدو أفضل كثيرًا.
We can see that for the lower ratings: three, four and five,
يمكننا أن نرى أنه بالنسبة للتصنيفات المنخفضة (ثلاثة وأربعة وخمسة)
red samples show higher proportions,
تظهر نسب أكبر من عينات النبيذ الأحمر،
and for the higher ratings: six, seven,
وبالنسبة للتصنيفات المرتفعة (ستة وسبعة
eight and nine, white samples have higher proportions.
وثمانية وتسعة) تظهر نسب أعلى من النبيذ الأبيض.
The data we're showing looks great,
تبدو البيانات التي نعرضها رائعة،
but the tick labels on the X axis look messy,
لكن تسميات التجزئة على المحور X تبدو فوضوية،
and it would be nicer to have the red and white bar for each rating next to each other.
وسيكون من الأفضل أن نجعل شريط النبيذ الأحمر وشريط النبيذ الأبيض لكل تصنيف متجاورين.
We're also missing a spot for the red samples with a quality rating of nine.
إننا نفقد أيضًا نقطة تخص عينات النبيذ الأحمر ذات تصنيف الجودة تسعة.
Although that number is zero,
رغم أن الرقم صفر
that spot should still be there.
فيُفترض أن تظل هذه النقطة موجودة.
Since there seems to be a lot of customization needed,
وحيث أنه يبدو أن هناك حاجة إلى الكثير من التخصيص،
it would make more sense to plot directly on Matplotlib than with pandas.
فسيكون رسم المخطط مباشرةً على Matplotlib أكثر منطقية من رسمه باستخدام pandas.
Before we move on, let's learn more about Matplotlib.
قبل التقدم في عملنا، فلنتعلم المزيد حول Matplotlib.